<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<object id="aUTm6phJC6PW" classes="paragraph" acceptedChildren=":Proteus-none" acceptedParents=":Proteus-any">
  <properties>
    <stringProperty name=":Proteus-name" category="general"><![CDATA[Clipboard]]></stringProperty>
    <dateProperty name=":Proteus-date" category="general">2024-07-31</dateProperty>
    <floatProperty name="version" category="general">1.0</floatProperty>
    <markdownProperty name="text" category="details"><![CDATA[In order to implement cut/copy/paste, a clipboard class was created to handle all the operations.

At first, Qt clipboard was used. It uses the system clipboard to store content. It was decided not to use the system clipboard because:

- Objects ID (ProteusID are used as clipboard content to allow cut/copy/operations. This content is irrelevant to the average user and might be confusing replacing users clipboard content with a ProteuID
- Ignoring the system clipboard makes easier the content handling and validation. KeyEvents and other events are handle in each specific widget if necessary.

The created class `Clipboard` is somewhere between a frontend and an application layer component. If it was created as a frontend `ProteusComponent` it would be harder to deal with circular dependencies and clipboard access across all frontend component (where the clipboard will be mostly accessed from), in the other hand making it a singleton adds the complexity of handling with the controller dependency injection when it is instantiated.

It was implement as a singleton and placed in the application layer. It is instantiated separately from everything else when the application boots in `app.py` and the controller is provided as dependency. The clipboard uses the state manager and the controller so it can be completely independent from any other resource when performing cut/copy/paste operations. This makes possible calling these clipboard methods from anywhere in the application.]]></markdownProperty>
    <markdownProperty name="comments" category="comments"><![CDATA[]]></markdownProperty>
  </properties>
  <children/>
  <traces>
    <traceProperty name="created-by" category="general" acceptedTargets="stakeholder" traceType=":Proteus-author">
      <trace target="4Shtuic5WXUn" traceType=":Proteus-author"/>
    </traceProperty>
    <traceProperty name="dependencies" category="dependencies" acceptedTargets="paragraph graphic-file external-resource glossary-item" traceType=":Proteus-dependency"/>
    <traceProperty name="source" category="dependencies" acceptedTargets="stakeholder" traceType=":Proteus-information-source"/>
  </traces>
</object>
